Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/harpreetset (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Artificial Intelligence
Natural Language Processing
Machine Learning

Languages

English Hindi

Certifications

Neural Networks for Machine Learning

APACHE SPARK AND SCALA

Machine Learning

Certified Scrum Master

Big Data and Hadoop – Instructor-Led Online Course

Harpreet Sethi

Lead Data Scientist (Artificial Intelligence & Machine Learning), Enterprise Architect-Emerging Technologies(RPA, Blockchain) Irvine, California

Summary

I am lead data scientist, seasoned architect and strong people manager with more than 20 years of experience. I am working as Solution Architect and Senior Data Scientist under Tax and Accounting division at CCH Wolters Kluwer. Having designed/ architected/implemented full pipeline of a wide range of Al/ ML, DevOps and Microservices based projects, with in depth understanding of Machine learning, Statistical modeling, deep neural networks, enterprise architecture and with strong ideology of being futuristic and innovative, I have the capability to come up with solutions that can help firms to achieve success smartly. I have been architecting and managing projects with small to large team sizes and people spread across different geographies. Currently I am working on building a pipeline for solving Document processing problem using my own custom algorithms. Not restricted to that, I have also worked on RPA based solutions for automating mundane tasks for our clients by adding cognitive robotic capabilities to their daily jobs and evaluating Blockchain based models to add to our suit of products.

Experience

Wolters Kluwer Lead Data Scientist and Enterprise Architect June 2017 - Present (2 years 10 months) California

I am working at Wolters Kluwer as Lead Data Scientist within Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning space. I am working on strategizing the adoption of AI in the firm by setting up Center of Excellence in data science and enhancing the product line by introducing AI to make them more smart for better customer experience. Currently I am working on smart Chatbots needed for Support Desk and computer vision based scanned document processing. Not restricted to that, I am also working on RPA based solutions for automating

mundane tasks for our clients by adding cognitive robotic capabilities to their daily jobs.

Publicis.Sapient
Senior Technology Architect and Data Scientist
January 2004 - June 2017 (13 years 6 months)

Companywide Global impact award winner for best architecture and program delivery model, a seasoned architect and strong people manager I worked with Publicis. Sapient Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning practice. Having worked on AI projects related to Chatbots and Game playing agents (for smart searches), designing deep networks to solve tough business problems and with strong ideology of being futuristic and innovative, I have the capability to come up with solutions that can help firms to achieve success smartly by solving complex business problems. I had architected and managed projects with various team sizes and spread across different geographies. I have delivered multiple full life cycle projects in capacity of playing various roles like architect, client manager, business analyst, program manager, account manager and engagement lead.

Magnasoft
Solutions Architect
June 1999 - January 2004 (4 years 8 months)

At Magnasoft I learnt and grew up to be a consultant who understands technology, and quickly turn around any complex problem and easy/ flexible to work with. I worked on multiple projects involving prototyping products designs and being part of Research and development

Education

Georgia Institute of Technology

Master of Science - MS, Computer Science

University of Pune BE, Instrumentation